Ashish Singh Baghel

Full Stack Web Developer | Digital Enthusiast | MCP | OCP | I.T. Analyst at Tata Consultancy Services Ltd

mechashishsingh@gmail.com

Summary

Digital technologies practitioner, Currently working on Modern Web Development, User Experience, DevOps, AWS Cloud Computing.

Professional experience of 4+ years, involved in design and development of business applications using Microsoft technologies for an insurance giant company based in USA.

Experience

Full Stack Web Developer | .Net/Digital, Modern Web Development at Tata Consultancy Services August 2018 - Present

Domain: BFS - (Banking and Finance Sector)

Professional Experience -

- Full stack development of business applications for a giant financial services company in Europe.

Full Stack Web Developer at Tata Consultancy Services

March 2014 - July 2018 (4 years 5 months)

Domain: Insurance

Position: Team Member

Professional Experience:

- Full Stack Web Development of business applications based on Microsoft technologies, Oracle DB for an Insurance giant client in USA.
- Experience in analysis of business systems and integrating it with main application.
- Involving initial concept through design, development, testing and deployment to end-user support and maintenance under MS Windows environment.
- Collaborating with different teams and client to ensure on time delivery. Experience in coordinating on-site and offshore team.
- Mentoring team members and working together to help in challenges.
- Ability to analyse root cause of issues and providing resolution.
- Requirement gathering for any proposed enhancements.
- Proposing solutions and implementing client approved solution.

- Creating and maintaining technical design document and other project related documents.
- Development in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, VB6.0, .NET Framework 2.0/3.5/4.0.
- Good experience in designing User Interface controls using HTML JavaScript and CSS.
- Integrating VB6.0 and .NET Framework code with REST API service calls.
- Programming in PL/SQL for existing/new Oracle DB packages and procedures.
- Installation and Setup of VB6.0 and .NET web apps in local developer Windows XP and Windows 7 machines.
- Test case preparation and unit testing.
- Configuration management of code.
- Pushing code in QA, STG environment. Coordinating with Infrastructure team with QA, STG deployment and fixing issues if any.
- Service Now experience to manage Incident tickets assigned to Web Development group as well as creating deployment request, service request, fault/failure tickets.
- Supporting UAT.
- Assisting client in moving developed code in production environment. Fixing prod deployment issues if any.
- Direct interaction with client.
- Sharing status updates with client and other stake holders.

Procurement Engineer at ETA Group of Companies July 2013 - February 2014 (8 months)

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Supply Chain Management in DMRC projects
- Indent Management
- Vendor Identification
- Procurement
- Material Delivery
- Vendor Payment etc.

Education

Rajiv Gandhi Prodyogiki Vishwavidyalaya Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Mechanical Engineering, 2009 - 2013

Ashish Singh Baghel

Full Stack Web Developer | Digital Enthusiast | MCP | OCP | I.T. Analyst at Tata Consultancy Services Ltd

mechashishsingh@gmail.com



Contact Ashish Singh on LinkedIn